

# CHARLES VERLEYEN

Ph.: +32 497 20 16 60 E-mail: charles.xavier.verleyen@gmail.com GitHub: Charles1104



## **OBJECTIVE**

Data Scientist seeking to work with an international data-oriented company where I will be able to put into practice my mix of soft and hard skills acquired through ten years of education and experience in different countries and sectors.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Data Scientist
 Aug 2017 – Nov 2017

Data Science Retreat (Berlin, Germany)

Strategic Sourcing Manager

Jul 2015 - Dec 2016

CTA Group (Antwerp, Belgium)

- o Management of the chemical consignment contracts for three gold mines in West Africa.
- o Developer of Business analytics reports using VBA in Excel

• **Project Manager** Cimko (Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo) Feb 2015 - Jul 2015

o Project management coordinator with all the departments, daily reporting to the GM and recruitments.

Procurement Manager

Jan 2014 – Jan 2015

Kempinski Hotel Fleuve Congo (Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo)

o Responsible for all the purchases of the hotel. Managed a team of eight persons.

• Supplier Quality Engineer

**Dec 2012 – Dec 2013** 

General Electric (San Luis Potosí, Mexico)

o Responsible for the procurement of electronic commodities from 30 suppliers.

## **EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT**

•	MOOC in "machine learning" and "data analysis with Python" – Coursera	Jul 2017 - Aug 2017
•	<b>Bootcamp in Web development</b> – Devleague (Hawaii)	Mar 2017 - Jun 2017
•	Msc in Business engineering - major in Supply Chain Management (cum laude) Louvain School of Management, Belgium and National University of Singapore	Sep 2009 - Jun 2012
•	Bsc in Business Engineering (cum laude) Université Catholique de Louvain, Belgium	Sep 2006 - Jun 2009

## LANGUAGES AND COMPUTER SKILLS

- **Human Languages:** French (native), English (fluent; 90%), Spanish (fluent; 90%), Dutch (intermediate; 50%)
- Computer Languages: Javascript (intermediate), NodeJS (intermediate), Python (intermediate), SQL (proficient), Sequelize (proficient), PostgreSQL (intermediate), HTML (intermediate) and CSS (intermediate).
- **Software Skills:** Microsoft office suite (VBA programmer), Microsoft Dynamic Nav 2013 & Jet reports, SAP (modules MM and PP), SAS (Certified Base Programmer for SAS 9), AnyLogic and Adobe suite.

## ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- **APICS CPIM certificate** (5 modules achived). Obtained in September 2012.
- Vice President of a renowned Junior Enterprise (LSM Conseil www.lsmconseil.com) from 2008 until 2010.
- **Volunteer in a South African camp** provided care to the animals (summer 2004).
- Sports enthusiast with active participation in Tennis and Swimming; Amateur of Horse Riding.
- Holder of "PADI Open Water Diver Certificate" and "PADI Advanced Open Water Certificate".